Guide to the William Campbell Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
William Campbell Papers
[ca. 1900]-1925.
Campbell, William.
2 linear ft (ca. 1,000 items in 4 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
MS#0186
4078579
This collection contains personal papers, correspondence, financial records and memorabilia relating to geologist and metallurgist, William Campbell.
Biographical Note
Geologist and metallurgist from Great Britain, joined the Columbia School of Mines faculty in 1902.
Scope and Content
Most of Campbell's papers are of a personal nature, including approximately 100 items of personal correspondence (incoming), his World War I naval records, his financial records, and memorabilia. There are a few miscellaneous letters relating to his academic career, some miscellaneous notes, and daily calendar memoranda. Included is a holograph laboratory notebook of the British metallurgist, Saville Shaw, with typescript transcripts of contents along with notes by Campbell.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in one series:
Series I: William Campbell Papers, [ca. 1900]-1925
Subjects
Columbia University.--School of Mines--Faculty.; Shaw, Saville.; World War, 1914-1918.; Metallurgical research.; Financial records.; Laboratory notebooks.; Photoprints.; College teachers.; Geologists.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: Boxes 2-4. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1965 M-65 Columbiana Transfer
- Series I: William Campbell Papers, [circa 1900]-1925
  - Miscellaneous letters (incoming), circa 1902-1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters of introduction and recommendation (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - World War I naval orders and papers (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Shaw, Saville. Holograph (?) notebook (with typescript transcripts of contents and some notes of Campbell) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Financial records. Investments, 1919-1924 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Daily calendar memoranda, 1911-1916 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Personal correspondence (incoming), circa 1900-1920 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Memorabilia (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Columbia programs, notices, letters of appointment, reprints, photographs, chiefly of Columbia University scenes (Box 3)
  - Financial records. Bank passbooks and cancelled checks (Box 4)